{
  "q1": [
    {
      "question": "William Mead and this man were accused of “speaking in Gracechurch Street,” but when the jury refused to a provide a guilty verdict, the judge starved the jury for two days before imprisoning them, too. This man wrote No Cross, No Crown while imprisoned in the Tower of London for allegedly denying the Trinity. In order to pay a debt to this man’s father, Charles II made this man the largest non-royal landowner in the world. For ten points, name this Quaker who founded an American colony governed from Philadelphia.",
      "answer": "William Penn"
    },
    {
      "question": "As a teenager, this thinker built a calculator to aid his father’s work as a tax supervisor. This man developed a law stating that a change in pressure at a point in a fluid is transmitted equally throughout the entire fluid. This man, who argued in support of Jansenism in Provincial Letters, names a diagram that conveniently displays the binomial coefficients; each value equals the sum of the two numbers above it in that “triangle.” For ten points, name this 17th century French polymath.",
      "answer": "Blaise Pascal"
    },
    {
      "question": "The Pont Neuf was completed during the reign of this French monarch; its financing was overseen by this man’s chief minister, Maximilien de Bethune, the Duke of Sully. This king’s mistress, Gabrielle d’Estr´ees [dess-tray], supposedly convinced him to proclaim that Paris was “well worth a mass” when he converted from Protestantism to Catholicism. For ten points, name this king who supported religious toleration via the Edict of Nantes, the first monarch from the House of Bourbon.",
      "answer": [
        "Henry IV",
        "Henry III of Navarre, but"
      ]
    },
    {
      "question": "One response to this event was delayed when David Ige [ee-gay] forgot his Twitter password. This event, which took place during a shift-change operation, involved a failure to hear the words “Exercise, exercise, exercise,” though it was originally blamed on a worker pressing the wrong button in a drop-down menu. The Emergency Alert System declared “THIS IS NOT A DRILL” during, for ten points, what January 13, 2018 event that caused a brief panic in Honolulu? ANSWER:2018Hawaiiballisticmissilefalsealarmincident(acceptdescriptiveanswersthatincorporate all three underlined ideas; prompt on answers with only one or two of the three underlined ideas; accept descriptions of a nuclear attack in place of ballistic missile; accept any place in Hawaii, including Honolulu before it is mentioned, in place of Hawaii) (5) This man was known as the “fierce” in his early years after murdering 99 of his 100 brothers. This man, who rose to power after tricking Sushima into a pit of hot coals, was traumatized by seeing the Daya river allegedly run red with blood in the Kalinga wars. This son of Bindusara erected a rock edict at Sarnath detailing the importance of good deeds and adherence to Dharma. For ten points, name this Mauryan ruler who converted to Buddhism.",
      "answer": "Ashoka the Great or Asoka the Great"
    },
    {
      "question": "One work in this genre describes three generations of tribesmen led by Seitek, Semetei, and Manas. The demon Adamastor is battled by a group of sailors in one of these pieces of literature that tells of Vasco de Gama’s voyage to India. Elias Lonrot compiled one of these works of literature from oral tradition, including the story of the creation of the Sampo. The Lusiads and the Kalevala are examples of, for ten points, what type of literature with a grand scope, such as the Odyssey?",
      "answer": [
        "epic poems",
        "national epics"
      ]
    },
    {
      "question": "Prior to this event, covering fire from David Conner’s Home Squadron allowed a commander to land his forces uncontested on Collado [co-yah-doh] Beach. Fighting centered around the fort of San Juan de Ulu´a during this event, which eventually forced the surrender of Juan Morales. After the battles of Monterrey and Buena Vista, Zachary Taylor’s forces were given to Winfield Scott in preparation for this campaign. For ten points, name this 1847 event that led to the capture of a key Mexican seaport.",
      "answer": "Siege of Veracruz"
    },
    {
      "question": "One artist from this country showed the key to city of Breda being surrendered to a general of this country’s army. In another work, the same artist included a self-portrait next to the reflection of this country’s King Phillip IV in a mirror. Another painter active in this country was born in Crete and painted a landscape showing a “View of” of this country’s city of Toledo [toh-LAY-doh]. For ten points, name this Iberian country home to the artist of Las Meninas, Diego Velazquez.",
      "answer": "Spain"
    },
    {
      "question": "This man wrote that Catholicism and Marxism were incompatible, as Marxism has been used as a weapon to disobey the Christian faith. David Yallop speculated that this man was poisoned to prevent further investigation of Paul Marcinkus and Roberto Calvi. This man’s death caused the most recent Year of Three Popes, as he was only in office for just over a month. For ten points, name this Pope who was succeeded in 1978 by Karol Wojtyla [voy-twah], a Polish cardinal whose papal name honored this man. ANSWER:John Paul I(orAlbinoLuciani;promptonJohnPaul;donotpromptonJohnorPaulalone) (10) This politician introduced a bill to reduce infant mortality that initially did not reach the floor, but inspired the creation of the Sheppard-Towner Act in the next Congress. After losing a Republican primary to Oscar Lanstrum, this politician ran with the National Party but finished third behind Lanstrum and Thomas Walsh. This politician reasoned “I can’t go to war, and I refuse to send anyone else” when she became the sole vote against declaring war on Japan. For ten points, name this Montana politician, the first female member of Congress.",
      "answer": "Jeannette Rankin"
    }
  ],
  "q2": [
    {
      "tossup": {
        "question": "This man resigned his rank of colonel after he was compared to Clement Vallandigham for a speech in which he blamed the British, Jews, and the presidency for pushing towards war. This man became the first ever Time Man of the Year after successfully completing a trip to Le Bourget that earned him the Orteig prize. The Spirit of St. Louis was flown by, for ten points, what American pilot who completed the first solo transatlantic flight?",
        "answer": "Charles Lindbergh"
      },
      "bonus": {
        "question": "Charles Lindbergh controversially became an advocate for this anti-Semitic political group that strongly opposed American entry into World War II. This group dissolved after Pearl Harbor.",
        "answer": "America First Committee or AFC"
      }
    },
    {
      "tossup": {
        "question": "This composer quoted the “Habanera” from Bizet’s [bee-zay’s] Carmen in the opening movement of a symphony whose finale was described as a “parody of shrillness” in the spurious autobiography Testimony. An opera by this composer focusing on Katerina Izmailova prompted Joseph Stalin to denounce him as “formalist” in the article “Muddle Instead of Music.” For ten points, what persecuted composer of Lady Macbeth of the Mtsensk District dubbed his Fifth Symphony “A Soviet Artist’s Reply to Just Criticism” and wrote fifteen symphonies in total?",
        "answer": "Dmitri Shostakovich"
      },
      "bonus": {
        "question": "“Muddle Instead of Music,” as well as an additional article denouncing Shostakovich entitled “Ballet Falsehood,” was published in what official Soviet newspaper?",
        "answer": "Pravda"
      }
    },
    {
      "tossup": {
        "question": "In this city, security guard Harald Jager [yay-ger] became a hero after refusing to stop a stampeding crowd. Tensions in this city were heightened as the result of a barricade erected in Operation Rose, culminating in a tank stand off near this city’s Checkpoint Charlie. During Ronald Reagan’s visit to this city, a request to “open this gate” was issued to Mikhail Gorbachev, along with a challenge to “tear down this wall.” For ten points, name this German city that was divided into east and west during the Cold War.",
        "answer": [
          "Berlin",
          "East and/or West Berlin"
        ]
      },
      "bonus": {
        "question": "The fall of the Berlin Wall and reunification of Germany was the biggest success of this West German chancellor. This mentor of Angela Merkel was later disgraced when the Christian Democrats were caught accepting illegal donations.",
        "answer": "Helmut Kohl"
      }
    },
    {
      "tossup": {
        "question": "This building’s shadow can be used to tell time, thanks to a nearby park designed in the shape of sundial. Three gold coins with rectangular holes are the logo of this building, which was designed to appear as multiple money boxes stacked atop each other in the feng shui style by architect C.Y. Lee. This was the world’s tallest building until 2010, when it was surpassed by the Burj Khalifa. For ten points, name this Taiwanese skyscraper.",
        "answer": "Taipei 101"
      },
      "bonus": {
        "question": "This Malaysian skyscraper was surpassed by Taipei 101 as the world’s tallest building in 2004, though it still holds the record as the tallest twin towers complex.",
        "answer": "Petronas Twin Towers"
      }
    },
    {
      "tossup": {
        "question": "This man accidentally sunk John Tyler’s attempts to annex Texas after a letter to Richard Pakenham hoping for the expansion of slavery was exposed. While serving as James Monroe’s Secretary for War, this man successfully set up the Bureau of Indian Affairs. This man penned an “Exposition and Protest” condemning the Tariff of Abominations, arguing that states should have a right to nullify federal laws. For ten points, name this member of the Great Triumvirate from South Carolina.",
        "answer": "John C. Calhoun"
      },
      "bonus": {
        "question": "During Calhoun’s vice presidency, his wife Floride provoked this scandal by refusing to speak with the Secretary of War’s wife over allegations of adultery.",
        "answer": [
          "Petticoat Affair",
          "Peggy Eaton Affair"
        ]
      }
    },
    {
      "tossup": {
        "question": "This empire was plunged into a series of civil wars after the assassinations of Berdibek and Janibeg, and it was dissolved after Akhmat backed down against troops from former vassal kingdoms at a standoff at the Ugra River. This empire’s power diminished after Dmitri Donskoy liberated Moscow at the Battle of Kulikovo. The cities of Old and New Sarai were capitals of, for ten points, what kingdom that stretched into Western Europe, a Mongol horde named for the color of its tents?",
        "answer": [
          "Golden Horde",
          "Kipchak Khanate"
        ]
      },
      "bonus": {
        "question": "At the Battle of Legnica [leh-neetz-ah], the Golden Horde infamously filled nine sacks with these body parts after removing them from their Polish prisoners.",
        "answer": "ears"
      }
    },
    {
      "tossup": {
        "question": "While working on his Ph.D. in this city, Frederic Thrasher undertook a comprehensive study of 1,313 of its gangs. Sudhir Venkatesh’s Gang Leader for a Day relied on field research in this city, where Venkatesh also collected data on prostitutes that was presented in a 2005 book. That work, Freakonomics, was co-written by Steven Levitt, an economics professor who works in this city. Twelve Nobel Prizes in Economics have been awarded to professors like Milton Friedman who teach in, for ten points, what Midwestern city?",
        "answer": "Chicago"
      },
      "bonus": {
        "question": "The Chicago school of economics generally rejects the theories of this British economist, who advocated deficit spending to spur economies out of recessions.",
        "answer": [
          "John Maynard Keynes , but be lenient",
          "Keynesian economics"
        ]
      }
    },
    {
      "tossup": {
        "question": "During this battle, citizens defended themselves by removing guns from the ship Aurora and mounting them atop the Pulkovo Heights. Operation Northern Light brought the Gustav rail gun from the Crimea to this battle. Defenders in this battle were resupplied via the “Road of Life,” where supplies were transported across the frozen Lake Ladoga. In 1941, Army Group North began, for ten points, what 900-day siege of a Russian city in World War II?",
        "answer": "Siege of Leningrad"
      },
      "bonus": {
        "question": "This country’s army, led by Carl Mannerheim, assisted the Nazis in the siege of Leningrad because this country was fighting the Soviets in the Continuation War at the time.",
        "answer": "Finland"
      }
    }
  ],
  "q3": [
    {
      "category": "Redistricting",
      "prompt": "Name the...",
      "questions": [
        {
          "question": "Number of Congressional districts in the US, equal to the size of the House of Representatives.",
          "answer": "435"
        },
        {
          "question": "Practice, named after a Massachusetts Senator, of redistricting to favor a particular party.",
          "answer": "gerrymandering"
        },
        {
          "question": "Justice, the first woman on the Supreme Court, whose opinion in Shaw v. Reno established strict scrutiny for racial redistricting.",
          "answer": "Sandra Day O’Connor"
        },
        {
          "question": "State, governed by Roy Cooper, where a federal court struck down a district map on partisan, rather than racial, grounds in 2018.",
          "answer": "North Carolina"
        },
        {
          "question": "Chief Justice who first ruled on redistricting issues, as well as Brown v. Board of Education.",
          "answer": "Earl Warren"
        },
        {
          "question": "1965 act whose Section Five required states with histories of discrimination to clear redistricting maps with the Department of Justice.",
          "answer": "Voting Rights Act of 1965"
        },
        {
          "question": "2013 Supreme Court case that weakened Section 5 preclearance and originated in an Alabama county.",
          "answer": "Shelby County v. Holder"
        },
        {
          "question": "1962 Supreme Court case that decided redistricting was not a political question and could be ruled upon.",
          "answer": "Baker vs. Carr or Carr vs. Baker"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "category": "Thirty Years’ War",
      "prompt": "Name the...",
      "questions": [
        {
          "question": "Hapsburg country led during the war by Philip IV from Madrid.",
          "answer": "Spain"
        },
        {
          "question": "Official religion of possessions of the Hapsburg family, which opposed the Protestant Union.",
          "answer": "Roman Catholicism"
        },
        {
          "question": "“Red Eminence,” an adviser to Louis XIII who oversaw French intervention during the war.",
          "answer": "Cardinal Richelieu or Armand Jean du Plessis"
        },
        {
          "question": "City where regents were defenestrated, or tossed out of a third-story window, to begin the war.",
          "answer": "Prague"
        },
        {
          "question": "Peace negotiated to conclude the war, the result of the treaties of Osnabru¨ck and Mu¨nster.",
          "answer": "Peace of Westphalia"
        },
        {
          "question": "Commander of Swedish forces during the Thirty Years’ War until his death at Lu¨tzen.",
          "answer": "Gustavus Adolphus"
        },
        {
          "question": "German city that was the site of a brutal 1631 sacking, the worst massacre of the war.",
          "answer": "Sack of Magdeburg"
        },
        {
          "question": "German town, the site of two key battles in the war: a 1634 victory in which tercios crushed the Swedish army, and a 1645 French victory.",
          "answer": "Battles of Nordlingen"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "category": "Famous Ships",
      "prompt": "Name the ship that...",
      "questions": [
        {
          "question": "Sunk on its maiden voyage in 1912 after hitting an iceberg, killing well over 1,000 people.",
          "answer": "RMS Titanic"
        },
        {
          "question": "Gained the nickname “Old Ironsides” after fighting the Guerriere.",
          "answer": "USS Constitution"
        },
        {
          "question": "Was Horatio Nelson’s flagship when he was shot at Trafalgar.",
          "answer": "HMS Victory"
        },
        {
          "question": "Destroyed the Hood at the Battle of Denmark Strait and was sunk three days later.",
          "answer": "Bismarck"
        },
        {
          "question": "Sunk, and is now a memorial, at Pearl Harbor.",
          "answer": "USS Arizona Memorial"
        },
        {
          "question": "Was the location of the Japanese surrender after World War II.",
          "answer": "USS Missouri"
        },
        {
          "question": "Sunk in 1945 after delivering the parts for Little Boy.",
          "answer": "USS Indianapolis"
        },
        {
          "question": "Had its entire crew go missing on an 1872 voyage to Genoa.",
          "answer": "Mary Celeste"
        }
      ]
    }
  ],
  "q4": [
    {
      "parts": [
        "(30 pts) A series of racially tinged riots in this city was triggered by Jos´e Diaz’s death, the Sleepy Lagoon murder. Modern Pentecostalism was developed at this city’s Foursquare Church by Aimee (20 pts)",
        "Semple MacPherson, a decade after the end of the Azusa Street Revival in this city. This city’s other race riots included a response to an attack on a motorist in its district of (10 pts)",
        "Watts, as well as a response to the beating of Rodney King. For ten points, name this large California city currently led by Mayor Eric Garcetti."
      ],
      "answer": "Los Angeles"
    },
    {
      "parts": [
        "(30 pts) At one of these places, police captain Johan Mahieu failed to prevent a concrete wall from crushing civilians; Mahieu was later convicted of manslaughter for his role in the Heysel disaster. After misassigning blame in the wake of the (20 pts)",
        "Hillsborough disaster at another of these structures, the Sun newspaper was banned from the city of Liverpool. White Hart Lane, another of these structures, was demolished in August 2017, so (10 pts)",
        "Tottenham Hotspur’s temporary home is now Wembley. Old Trafford and Anfield are other examples of, for ten points, what European sporting venues for teams like Manchester United?"
      ],
      "answer": [
        "European football stadiums",
        "Belgian football stadiums before “Hillsborough” is read"
      ]
    },
    {
      "parts": [
        "(30 pts) In the Treaty of Ryswick, Spain formally recognized French control of Acadia and a colony in this location. In this location, the one-armed Fran¸cois Mackandal led raids on plantation owners. Shortly before the dissolution of a colony here, it was struck by an outbreak of (20 pts)",
        "yellow fever that killed general Charles Leclerc. A decade-long slave revolt here was led by figures like (10 pts)",
        "Jean-Jacques Dessalines and Toussaint Louverture. The French colony of Saint-Domingue [sahn doh-MEENG] was located in, for ten points, what modern-day country on the western half of Hispaniola?"
      ],
      "answer": "Haiti"
    },
    {
      "parts": [
        "(30 pts) This man employed James Alexander, who was quickly found in contempt; Andrew Hamilton and William Smith then defended him. This man, upset over the promotion of James DeLancey to replace Lewis (20 pts)",
        "Morris, was condemned for his “scandalous [...] and seditious reflections” by William Cosby; this man’s supporters noted, though, that (10 pts)",
        "truth is a defense against charges of libel. For ten points, name this German-American editor whose 1735 trial became a landmark defense of freedom of the press."
      ],
      "answer": "John Peter Zenger"
    },
    {
      "parts": [
        "(30 pts) This nation’s diplomats were forced to attend a peace conference held atop barges after they suffered defeats at the Battles of Eylau and Friedland. After violating the subsequent treaty, this nation used the (20 pts)",
        "Unicorn artillery piece, the Bagration Fleches, and the Raevsky redoubt to defend its home soil at (10 pts)",
        "Borodino. Because this nation refused to follow the Treaty of Tilsit and join the Continental System against Britain, it was invaded in 1812. A harsh winter helped thwart Napoleon’s invasion of, for ten points, what country led by Tsar Alexander I?"
      ],
      "answer": "Russian Empire"
    },
    {
      "parts": [
        "(30 pts) These people were suppressed in one country after Antoine de La Valette went bankrupt on land deals in the Caribbean. These people upset the Marquis of Pombal by defending so-called “Reductions” that housed Guarani natives in (20 pts)",
        "South America. Clement XIV refused to meet with a leader of this group, Lorenzo Ricci, and ultimately suppressed them in 1773. The Tavora Affair ended with the (10 pts)",
        "expulsion of these people from Portugal, making teaching of the Spirtiual Exercises illegal. For ten points, name this powerful missionary order that was founded by Ignatius of Loyola."
      ],
      "answer": [
        "Jesuits",
        "members of the Society of Jesus"
      ]
    },
    {
      "parts": [
        "(30 pts) A lone rider before this battle offered “seven feet of English ground” to this battle’s losing commander, saying “he is taller than most men.” During this battle, a (20 pts)",
        "Norse axeman held up the winning side’s troops on a bridge until he was speared by a soldier from under the bridge. Tostig, the brother of the winning commander of this battle, was killed in it. Following this battle, another force (10 pts)",
        "landed at Pevensey. Harald Hardrada died in a defeat to Harold Godwinson at, for ten points, what September 1066 battle, fought three weeks before Hastings?"
      ],
      "answer": "Battle of Stamford Bridge"
    },
    {
      "parts": [
        "(30 pts) In this city, Fort Independence stands at the site of Castle Williams, which once housed governor Thomas Hutchinson after an angry mob broke into his home. A declaration that “this (20 pts)",
        "meeting can do nothing further to save the country” was given at this city’s Old South Meeting House, beginning an insurrection. This city’s (10 pts)",
        "harbor was closed in the Coercive Acts after people dressed as Mohawks smashed crates of Darjeeling aboard ships. For ten points, name this city whose harbor was the site of an infamous 1773 tea party."
      ],
      "answer": "Boston"
    }
  ]
}